Previously on Transformers Prime...
在上一集里
Four sets of coordinates from Alpha Trion remain encrypted.
钛师傅的讯息里还剩下四个加密坐标
It is logical to conclude that each corresponds to the location of one of the Omega keys.
我们可以推断出那就是终极之钥的位置
Scrap!
糟了！
It appears identical to the one taken from me by Optimus Prime.
这个和擎天柱从我手中抢走的一模一样
Pieces of a larger puzzle, perhaps.
或许 这只是拼图中的一块？
Alpha Trion said we need all four keys
钛师傅说过我们得把四个钥匙都弄到手
to restore Cybertron, remember?
才能让塞博特恩重生 记得吗？
We just need to hang on to the one we have,
我们只要保护好手头上的
find a way to get the others back from Megatron.
再想法从威震天那里把剩下的抢过来就行了
The final entry has been decoded.
最后一个坐标也破解了
The coordinates are forming an image.
坐标正在形成一幅图像
Smokescreen?
这是烟幕？！
Prime's latest recruit is the final relic of Iacon!
擎天柱的新兵是最后一个铁堡遗物？
No!
不！
Wakey, wakey.
太阳晒屁股啦！
What?!
啥？！
If you're looking for your Phase Shifter, finders keepers.
你在找相位仪么？谁找到归谁！
Enough prattling, Knockout!
少耍嘴皮子 击倒！
Hand me the final Iacon relic... now.
把最后一个铁堡遗物交出来 快！
Yeah, I can't really help you.
唔…这我真的无能为力
That's the only one I was packing.
我只有一个相位仪
Soundwave.
声波
You got the wrong guy, chief.
你搞错了 威总
Optimus Prime's the one who can decode the Iacon database.
擎天柱才是唯一能破译铁堡数据库的人
Ah, but you misunderstand.
啊…可搞错的人是你
The final entry has been decoded by us!
最后一个数据已经被我们破解了！
And according to our findings,
根据我们的发现
it would appear I do indeed have the right guy.
显然我手上的人才是“真命天子”
The question is, what is it that you are still packing?
问题在于你的身上到底还藏着什么
Why, hidden treasure, of course!
哇哦 果然腹中有乾坤！
Smokescreen must have been taken aboard the Decepticon warship.
烟幕肯定是被带上霸天虎战舰了！
Tracing his signal through its shielding will be impossible.
没法穿透战舰的屏障追踪他的信号
Continue monitoring all frequencies, Ratchet.
继续监控所有频道 救护车
Far more than Smokescreen's fate may be at stake.
危在旦夕的不仅仅是烟幕的命运
I... don't get it. How could Smoke be an Omega key?
我还是不明白 烟幕怎么会成为终极之钥？
Perhaps he isn't the key, but its container.
或许他并非钥匙本身 而是装载钥匙的容器？
The other Iacon relics were sent to Earth in pods.
其他铁堡遗物是用宇宙舱送来的
Why not this one?
为何独此与众不同？
When the Decepticons stormed Iacon,
或许当霸天虎洗劫铁堡时
it may have been too late for Alpha Trion
钛师傅已来不及将最后一个钥匙送入太空了
at least, by standard means.
…至少常规方法已经行不通了
So Smokescreen assumed everything went black because he was hit by Decepticons.
那么当烟幕昏迷时 他以为是被霸天虎打的
But Alpha Trion's the one who actually turned out the kid's lights.
但实际上那是钛师傅所为
It stands to reason that my mentor did not want Smokescreen to know
考虑到我的导师担心烟幕 被敌人俘获而向他隐瞒事实
And with a mobile relic,
既然遗物是活动的
Alpha Trion couldn't possibly supply fixed coordinates.
钛师傅自然无法提供确切的坐标
So the big "A" slipped us a clue instead... Smoke's mug shot.
于是钛大爷转而扔给我们一个线索 烟仔的大头照！
But the Decepticons got to Smokescreen first.
但霸天虎抢先抓走了烟幕
I fear they have decoded the same clue.
恐怕他们也破解了同一个线索
Yet another of these identical relics?
又是一个一模一样的遗物？
Remove it swiftly.
快把它取出来！
With pleasure.
乐意效劳
I do so resent a finish flashier than my own.
人家一向讨厌比我还闪亮的漆面
Ha! Made you squirm.
哈 吓着你了吧！
Trippy.
梦幻般的效果…
And intuitive.
…还可随意操控
Proper grounding ensures that its user won't phase through the floor.
适当的接地功能 能防止使用者陷入地板
I said swiftly.
我让你快点！
Ah. Ah. Get your stinkin' hand out of my gears!
啊 啊 把你的脏手拿开！
Mm, and... gotcha!
嗯…这不是…拿到啦！
Tell me the function of these relics.
告诉我这些遗物作何用途！
Doorstops? Shavers? Bling? Beats me.
门钩？刮胡刀？首饰？这可难住我了
Hmm. A pity this little gadget won't allow me to just reach into his brain pan and
哼 可惜这小玩意儿不能让我探进他的大脑
pluck out the info.
把那些情报一把拽出来
Fortunately, we possess a device that can.
幸运的是 我们拥有这样的设备
Individually, each of these so-called Omega keys is useless.
尽管单个终极之钥毫无用处
Yet possessing even a single one grants me tremendous negotiating power
但这仍能大大增加我的谈判筹码
with either Autobots or Decepticons.
不管对方是汽车人还是霸天虎
Still, imagine if I manage to acquire the other three.
不过 想像一下我成功得到其他三个的话…
I could revive Cybertron and seize the throne as Starscream the first.
我可以让塞博特恩重生！ 并以“红蜘蛛一世”之名称帝…
Supreme overlord and emperor of destruction!
至高无上的霸主！破坏大帝！
But unlike Megatron,
可我不像威震天
I lack the necessary infrastructure to enforce such a reign.
我没有建立这种强权统治的基础条件
No warship, no army... only my meager laboratory finds,
没有战舰 没有军队 只有这破实验室里的东西
a ground-bridge remote control, a single remaining dose of Red Energon,
一个环陆桥的遥控开关 最后一剂红色能量液
and you, old friend.
还有你 老朋友…
But I would all too gladly trade this
不过 我很乐意用这东西做笔交易
simply to be restored to my former glory.
只为恢复以往的荣耀…
While I am unfamiliar with the lore of these Omega keys,
我并未听说过这些终极之钥
Alpha Trion knew many secrets,
但钛师傅知道很多秘密
and the ancients possessed technology
我们的先祖拥有许多神奇的科技
that has long been lost to what we consider modern science.
在我们的现代科学中早已失传
Whatever their function, this much is certain.
尽管还不清楚功能和原理 但有一件事可以确定
We cannot restore Cybertron without all four Omega keys in our possession.
那就是只有集齐四枚终极之钥 才能让塞博特恩复苏
The future of our home world depends on it.
故乡的未来就指望它了！
That's a wrap.
观影结束
The power to remake Cybertron as I see fit.
可以依我意愿…再造塞博特恩的力量…
I will pry the other two keys from Optimus Prime's lifeless fingers.
我会杀了擎天柱 夺回另外两枚钥匙
We must find the exact location of the Autobot base.
我们必须找到汽车人基地的确切位置
Patch in and tear apart Smokescreen's mind, if you must.
必要的话 把烟幕的脑子撬开都行
Me?
由我来？
Who else?
你说呢？
Do you think I would entrust you to see this key safely to the vault containing the other one?
你以为我会把护送钥匙的重任交付给你吗？
Once more, into the brain pan.
呼…还是继续撬脑壳吧
No! Not again! Stay out of my head!
不！别来了！别动我的脑袋！
Now, now. You'll only make things worse for yourself.
安分点儿 乱动只会让你的情况更糟
Worse how?
更糟？怎么个糟法？
Well, aren't you the clever one?
有一套啊 你这小滑头
This is ship is miles in the sky and swarming with Decepticons!
这艘船在万里高空之上 船上遍布霸天虎
Do you really think you can escape?
你真的以为自己可以逃脱？
Who says I'm lookin' to escape?
谁说我要逃了？
Think fast!
灵机一动！
What?!
什么？！
Oh, this isn't the way out?
出口不在这边儿？
The keys.
交出钥匙！
A pity you are incapable of flight.
可惜你不会飞
Yeah, like I'm gonna let that stop me.
切 好像我会怕似的？
Smokescreen's signal, it's back online!
烟幕的信号又出现了！
The kid escaped the warship!
这小子逃出了战舰！
Smokescreen to base. I could really use a ground bridge.
烟幕呼叫基地 我非常需要环陆桥！
Retrieve the Omega keys! Quickly!
快去抢终极之钥 快！
Fliers! I need fliers!
会飞的！我需要会飞的！
Setting coordinates. Strange.
设定坐标 怪了…
What's the problem?
有什么问题？
Smokescreen's telemetry data doesn't make sense.
烟幕的遥测数据不对劲
I can't lock onto his position.
我无法锁定他的位置！
I've isolated the problem.
我发现问题所在了
Smokescreen is in free fall.
烟幕正在自由落体！
Smokescreen, I'm opening the ground bridge directly below you.
烟幕 我要在你的正下方开启环陆桥！
Brace yourselves. I'm gonna make an entrance.
各位留神 我马上要进来了
He's... off course.
他…偏离路线了！
You missed?
你算偏了？
Open another one... fast!
再开一个 快！
I hope proper grounding on this thing doesn't apply to actual ground.
希望这接地功能 对实际地面不起作用！
No!
不！
Scour the wreckage!
检查所有残骸！
I want those keys!
把钥匙给老子找出来！
Hey, Ratchet.
嘿 救护车？
I could still really use that ground bridge.
我还是需要环陆桥！
Did I tell you?
我早说了吧？
Destiny! Alpha Trion knew I'd keep it safe.
宿命！钛师傅知道我能保护好它！
Nice work, kid.
干得不错 后生！
It was the only key in Megatron's vault.
威震天那儿就这一把钥匙
Then three keys are accounted for.
那么现在有三枚钥匙了
Then the fourth is still somewhere on the Cons' warship.
第四枚仍在虎子战舰上的某处
Unless... Megatron never had it to begin with?
除非…威震天一开始就没拿到那一个？
A high-frequency signal...
高频信号
with an embedded message.
隐藏着一条信息
Starscream.
是红蜘蛛
"I have obtained something of interest to you
我捡到了一个你们很想要的东西
which seems to be of no practical use to me".
但似乎对我来说用处不大
It's got to be the Omega key!
肯定是终极之钥！
He's the one who blindsided me!
他就是打我闷棍的那混蛋！
What else could Scream be referring to?
除此之外别无可能
I only ask for the surgical replacement of my T-Cog in return."
作为交换 我只要求为我进行一次变形齿轮移植手术
Heh! Like we're gonna give scream back his wings.
哈！说得好像我们会把他的翅膀还给他！
Without the missing key, Cybertron will remain devoid of life.
没有那把钥匙 塞博特恩将永无生机
Broken record, I know, but... it could be a trick.
我知道 这是破天荒的机会 但那可能是个圈套
It is possible that Starscream does not yet realize
红蜘蛛可能还不知道
the significance of what he holds.
所持之物的重大意义
And we do know that he's been incapable of flight for some time.
而且我们也知道他很久不能飞了
The stakes are too great for us not to consider Starscream's proposal.
事关重大 我们必须考虑红蜘蛛的要求
However, we will take precautions.
尽管如此 我们仍须小心戒备
There.
在那儿！
Starscream, show us the Omega key.
红蜘蛛？交出终极之钥
Give it up, Scream.
放弃吧 小红！
Huh?
哈？
We're too late.
太迟了
The T-Cog won't help him now.
变形齿轮也帮不了他了
It would seem I have the run of the place.
看来这地儿现在由我做主
Oh, how easy it would be to gut you.
哦…现在掏出你的心是多么容易啊！
To gut all of you.
干掉你们所有人！
But... first thing's first.
可惜 本座另有要事…
Where does Optimus keep his key ring?
擎天柱把钥匙都放哪儿了？
Not here. Nope. No.
不在这儿 不在 不在
Ah! Do they think I have all day?
啊 这些人是不是以为我很闲！
Ah, there you are.
啊 在这儿呐！
Curious. Starscream has been deceased for quite some time.
奇怪 红蜘蛛死了有段时间了…
Well, how's that possible if he just sent us a message?
那怎么可能？他才刚给咱们发了消息啊
We have been deceived.
我们中计了！
Whoa! Whoa! What was that?
喔哦 这是怎么了？
Arcee, close the ground bridge now.
阿尔茜 关掉环陆桥！
Now that I have your trinkets,
现在我拿到了你们的小玩意儿
I'm free to enjoy slitting your...
我终于有空刮花你的…
But, as I appear to be pressed for time...
哼 可惜本座得赶时间…
Autobots.
汽――车――人――
Maintain positions!
原――地――驻――守――
I'm sorry. What was that?
抱歉 你说什么？
Wo.. oh... woo... oh...
呜哇哦哇…
You Autobots think you're so superior,
你们汽车人总以为自己多么优越
but do you know what you really are?
可实际上呢？
Slow!
迟钝！
The red energon wore off, didn't it?
红色能量耗尽了 是不？
He has the Omega keys!
他拿着终极之钥！
Come on!
快点儿！
No!!!
不――！！！
We'll get them back.
我们会抓住他的
The keys can be of no use to Starscream
钥匙对红蜘蛛一点用也没有
while he scrounges in the wild like some scraplet.
他不过是像吸屑虫一样见什么咬什么！
There must be something that we can offer him in exchange.
我们肯定能拿什么东西和他交换！
The fate of Cybertron now rests in Starscream's hands...
无论红蜘蛛有何企图
Whatever his intention.
塞博特恩的命运都掌握在他手中了
I beg you, my liege,
求您了 陛下
release me from this absurd predicament!
请将我从这窘境中解脱出来吧！
No! You shall serve as a constant reminder to those who dare
不！你正好给那些胆敢让我失望之人
fail me.
做个警示！
I cannot allow Optimus Prime to be the one to revive Cybertron.
我不能允许擎天柱成为塞博特恩的救世主！
We will locate the Autobot base, invade it, and retrieve the Omega keys.
我们一定要找到汽车人基地 然后进攻 夺回终极之钥！
Been there... done that.
我已经去过了 且大功告成
Please pardon my unannounced visit, lord Megatron.
请原谅我的不请自来 威震天陛下
But I have come bearing a peace offering.
小人有礼物敬呈于您…